The term Delta means a difference between
Delta という用語は二つの値の間の
two values. The deltaTime property of the
差分を示します。 Time クラスの deltaTime プロパティは
time class is essentially the time
要するに
between each update or fixed update
Update または FixedUpdate のコールの間の
function call. This can be used to smooth out
時間の間隔です。これによって動作に使用する値を
values used for movement and other
スムージングしたり、他の増分を伴う
incremental calculations.
計算に使用します。
The time between frames is not constant.
フレームの間の時間は一定ではありません。
So if, for example, you're moving an
このため、もし例えば各フレームにおけるオブジェクトを
object in each frame by a fixed amount
ある固定の量だけ移動する場合
then the overall effect might not be smooth.
全体の結果はスムーズでないかもしれません。
This is because the amount of time it takes
これはひとつのフレームを完了するための時間が
to complete a frame will vary,
一定ではないためであり、
despite the distance of movement
一方で動作の距離は一定となるためです。
remaining constant. If you modify the change
もし差分を Time.deltaTime を使用して修正すれば
using time.deltaTime then any frames that
おり長い時間を要したフレームは
take a longer time will see a bigger change.
その分だけより大きな距離変化します。
And any frames that take a shorter time
反対により短い時間を要したフレームは
will see a smaller change.
その分だけより短い距離変化します。
The overall effect of this is that over a period
これによる全体的なこうかとしては、一定の期間の間
of time the change will appear smooth
変化はスムーズに見えるようになり
as is shown in this demonstration.
次のデモの通りです。
Let's see this in action. When the scene
それでは実際の動作で確認してみます。シーンが始まる時
starts our countdown variable is reduced
countdown 変数は
by the amount of time, in seconds,
秒単位で、各フレームを完了するのに
that it takes to complete each frame.
要する時間の量に応じて減ります。
And when this reaches 0 we are enabling a
そしてこれが 0 に到達するとき、powerCube ゲームオブジェクトにて
light component on our power cube game object.
Light Component を有効化します。
At the same time we can control the cube
同時に、キューブの動作を制御することが出来ます。
movement. Here we are modifying the X axis
ここではオブジェクトの X 軸の変化量は
of the object when the right arrow
右矢印キーが押下されたとき、
key is pressed by adding an amount
speed 変数により
defined by the variable 'speed'
定義される量に
and modified by Time.deltaTime.
Time.deltaTime を掛け算します。
The movement is smoothed so that the speed
動作はスムージングされて、たとえフレームレートの間隔が一定でなくとも
remains constant, even if the frame rate
スピードは一定となります。
varies. The effect of using Time.deltaTime
こうして Time.deltaTime を使用するメリットは
in this way is that it gives
フレームあたりの変化量でなく
a change in values per second
秒あたりの変化量として
rather than per frame.
与えることが出来ることです。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)